## **EDUCATION**

THE CHINESE UNIVERSITY OF HONG KONG

Bachelor of Science in Quantitative Finance, 2016-2020

- Minor : Computer Science

- GPA: 3.65/4.0

- Anticipated Graduation : Dec 2020

## **ABOUT ME**

Motivational and innovative data science professional possessed with financial expertise, with international experience in AXA, Quant China, Avant Capital and Mass Mutual. Dependable and organized team player with the ability to communicate effectively and efficiently. Proven success in data science project, data engineering, and financial data analysis.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming: Python, R, Bash, VBA

Tools: Bloomberg, AWS
Database: SQL and No-SQL
Finance: Interest Rate Model

FINANCE

**STATISTICS** 

DATABASE

MACHINE LEARNING

LINUX & BASH

**AWS** 



expert

# KWAN TAK HEI, Fergus

Mobile: +852 6125 5752 E-mail: takhei611@gmail.com

Linkedin: https://linkedin.com/in/tak-hei-kwan

GitHub: https://github.com/heamabc

Personal Website: https://fergus-quant.herokuapp.com

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **DATA SCIENTIST**

AXA HK, Hong Kong, Sep 2019 - Present

- Streamlined the logic and structure of existing machine learning models
- Performed data mining and processing on data in database
- Utilized statistical analysis and machine learning algorithms to identify characteristics of cross-selling policies

#### QUANTITATIVE ANALYST

Quant China (Shenzhen), Shenzhen, Mar 2019 - Aug 2019

- Performed features generation and engineering on 50 CTA factors of commodity futures
- Applied stacking of different decision trees methods
- Obtained deep understanding of decision tree method and model selection

#### **QUANTITATIVE ANALYST**

Avant Capital Management (HK) Ltd., Hong Kong, Oct 2018 - Feb 2019

- Developed and backtested various trading strategies based on quantitative method
- Introduced rigorous statistical calculation into trading strategies to ensure the existence of the statistical property (ADF test, half-life, Hurst Exponent)
- Minimized the sophistication and risk-and-return ratio of the strategy

#### RECENT PROJECT

#### MACHINE LEARNING FUTURES TRADING STRATEGY

GitHub: https://github.com/heamabc/Machine-Learning-on-Futures

- Utilized and optimized several machine learning models including boosting decision trees
- Generated up to 30 features of commodity futures for machine to achieve greatest accuracy
- Analyzed and compared the impact of different features and application of different models

#### PAIR TRADING STRATEGY

GitHub: https://github.com/heamabc/Pair-Trading-Stategy

- Performed statistical tests, ADF test, half-life test, and Hurst Exponenet test
- Examined baskets of fundamentally and statistically correlated US stocks
- Achieved 1.6 sharpe ratio

# **ADDITIONAL ACTIVITIES**

THE GOLDEN Z CLUB, THE STUDENT UNION OF THE CUHK President, Feb 2017 - Jan 2018

• Organized 20 activities throughout the year, including 14 charity events

# FUTURES TRADING COMPETITION

Wing Fung Financial Group, Apr 2017 - Nov 2017

• Obtained a 202% profit ratio at the end of the competition